Seduce. Deceive. Repeat.
Red Sparrow is a thriller, mystery film directed by Francis Lawrence.
Prima ballerina Dominika Egorova faces a bleak and uncertain future
after she suffers an injury that ends her career.
She soon turns to Sparrow School, a secret intelligence service that trains
exceptional young people to use their minds and bodies as weapons.
Dominika emerges as the most dangerous Sparrow after
completing the sadistic training process.
As she comes to terms with her new abilities, she meets a CIA agent who
tries to convince her that he is the only person she can trust.
Dominika Egorova, played by Jennifer Lawrence.
Nathaniel "Natan" Nash, played by Joel Edgerton.
Vanya Egorov, played by Matthias Schoenaerts.
Matron, played by Charlotte Rampling.
Vladimir Korchnoi, played by Jeremy Irons.
Alexei Zyuganov, played by Ciarán Hinds.
Red Sparrow is a 2018 American spy thriller film directed by Francis Lawrence and written by
Justin Haythe, based on the 2013 novel of the same name by Jason Matthews.
The film stars Jennifer Lawrence, Joel Edgerton, Matthias Schoenaerts, Charlotte
Rampling, Mary-Louise Parker, Jeremy Irons, and Ciarán Hinds.
It tells the story of a former-ballerina-turned-Russian intelligence officer, who is sent to
make contact with a CIA officer in the hope of discovering the identity of a mole.
Matthews, a former member of the CIA, advised the
production on the depiction of spying.
Based on historic Soviet sexpionage and contemporary Russian use of
kompromat, filming took place in Hungary, Slovakia and Austria.
Red Sparrow premiered at the Newseum in Washington, D.C., on February 15,
2018, and was released in the United States on March 2, 2018.
The film grossed $151 million worldwide, and received mixed reviews from critics, who described it as having "more style than substance" and
criticized the film's long runtime and over-reliance on graphic violence and sex, although Lawrence's performance was praised.
The film explores themes of central intelligence agency (cia), sexual abuse,
budapest, hungary, based on novel or book, self sacrifice.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and thought_provoking.